SAI BHASKER RAJU CHITTAPRAGADA

<u>schittap@uwo.ca</u> | (226)-998-4770 | Unit 60, 70 Chapman Court, London, ON, Canada http://saibhaskerraju.tk | https://www.linkedin.com/in/saibhaskerraju/

Professional Summary:

Professional with over 3 years of working experience involved in all phases of software development seeking to combine practical experience in a dynamic IT environment; dedicated to team success in both individual and group settings; possess excellent problem-solving skills & research abilities and a strong background in software development, databases and Microsoft's Technology Stack.

Education:

Master of Engineering – Software Engineering The University of Western Ontario, London, ON, CA Aug 2020 GPA - current

Concentration: Full Stack Web Development, Data Analytics, Machine Learning

Professional Experience:

Cognizant Technology Solutions - Hyderabad, India

Oct 2018 - August 2019

Programmer Analyst

Developed REST APIs for "TheFA - Matchday" using C# and deployed to Azure API Management Portal for end users to consume without any latency.

- Developed APIs for showing LIVE status of matches to keep users posted.
- Developed APIs to display payment dues of players for signed up matches.
- Worked on security improvements of REST API like authorization and authentication.
- Implemented design patterns to maintain code re-usability and maintainability

Environment: C#.NET, Azure Logic Apps, Azure API Management

Prolifics Corporation - Hyderabad, India

July 2016 - Oct 2018

Associate Software Engineer

Created SSIS Packages for Hudson Advisors for their daily ETL Operations. We efficiently loaded high volume data per day And gracefully handled errors to manage failures.

- Revamped the existing logic to import huge unstructured excel sheet data into database using C# and Spreadsheet Gear to streamline overall data loading process and error logging.
- Migrated on-premise applications and data-loading operations into Azure SQL Warehouse and Amazon Redshift leveraging the power of cloud to speed up the ETL process.
- Earned " RACE " Award Twice for outstanding performance in Data migration from on-premise to Azure.
- Accelerated the data loading process by using In-Memory Tables as stage tables in SQL Server.
- Reduced the deployment time to 5min by automating the continuous integration process using PowerShell scripts.

Environment: C#.NET, Azure Logic Apps, Azure SQL Datawarehouse, PowerShell, SSIS, SQL Server, S3 Bucket, Amazon Redshift.

Voluntary Experience:

• Microsoft Student Partner

March 2015 - April 2016

Student Trainer and Campus Ambassador

• Delivered hands-on training sessions in my college to enable students on fundamentals of Azure. These activities were part of Azure Learning to empower students on latest technologies

• Firefox Student Ambassador

March 2015 - April 2016

Student Trainer and Campus Ambassador

- Trained students on Web technologies like HTML5, CSS3, JS by starting in-class training sessions.
- Launched a programming club in my college to build and start a developer community that builds apps for a better future

Certifications:

• Certified Blockchain Developer from Blockchain Council

Jan 2018